《飓风营救2》
（阿尔巴尼亚）
（特罗波耶）
He slaughtered our men…
他屠杀我们的人民
our brothers…
我们的兄弟
our sons.
我们的孩子
The dead cry out to us for justice.
必须要为他们讨回公道
On their souls，I swear to you.
我以亡灵的名义 向你们起誓
The man who took our loved ones from us.
那个夺去我们挚爱的人
The man who has brought us such pain and sorrow.
那个带给我们无尽痛苦和悲伤的人
We will find him.
我们会找到他
We will bring him here.
我们会把他带回来
We will not rest
我们将不眠不休
until his blood flows into this very ground.
直到他的鲜血洒满这片土地
We will have our revenge.
我们一定要血债血偿
（洛杉矶）
（洗车场）
- Sir？Excuse me。- Yeah.
- 先生 打扰一下 - 什么事
The finish is included in the cost of the wash.
洗车的费用里包含了抛光
That's okay，I'd rather do it myself.
不要紧 我喜欢自己来
I'm a little obsessive that way.
我有点强迫症
- Lenore。- Bryan.
- 丽诺尔 - 布莱恩
Hi。How are you？
最近还好吗
Fine。You？
不错 你呢
Mmm，good，good.
我也很好
Is something up？
有什么事吗
No。It's Saturday，two o'clock.
没事 今天周六 两点了
Kim's driving lesson？
金姆不是要上驾驶课吗
Uh… music lesson got switched.
她和音乐课调换了
The Tuesday one or the Friday one？
换的星期二的还是星期五的
I have no idea.
我也不清楚
You know how kids are.
孩子嘛 你知道的
Especially the ones who are desperate
特别是拼了命
to pass their driving test at the third try.
想通过第三次驾校考试的孩子
She's not desperate.
她没有那么渴望通过
But she failed the test twice，
但她前两次都没通过
Lennie。It's important.
莉妮 这很重要
So，where is she，really？
所以 她到底去哪了
I've never been a good liar，have I？
我从来都不擅长说谎 是吧
No，it's not your forte.
确实 说谎不是你的强项
She's at her boyfriend.
她去她男朋友那了
She has a boyfriend？
她交男朋友了
Do you want to come in for a drink？
要进来喝杯水吗
- Yeah。- Yeah。I think you should.
- 好的 - 我想也是
Why didn't she tell me，for god's sake？
老天 她怎么都不告诉我呢
She probably didn't want you running a full security check…
大概是不想你把她男友从幼儿园开始
of everything he's done since kindergarten.
所有的情况都给调查一遍吧
But she's okay，right？
但她没事吧
Yeah，she's okay.
是的 她没事了
Lennie，tell me it's none of my business…
莉妮 我知道这不关我的事
but are you okay？
但你还好吗
No.
不好
Not really.
算不上好
We've separated.
我们分居了
Lennie，if there's anything I can do…
莉妮 如果有什么我能帮上忙的
Well，I better…
我想我还是
Thanks for the wine.
谢谢你的红酒
Bryan.
布莱恩
Don't.
别去
I don't even know where the kid lives.
我都不知道那孩子住哪里
You found her in a city of 12 million people
你曾经在72小时内
within 72 hours.
在一座1200万人口的城市里找到她
Promise me.
答应我
- I just told you… - Promise.
- 我刚刚已经说了 - 答应我
I'm going to give her her space.
我会给她空间的
*Let me show you what I know*
让我告诉你我知晓的一切
*Let me take you where I'll go*
让我带你去我要去的地方
*I want to，yeah，share with you*
我想与你一起分享
*Why won't you let me show you？*
为什么不让我说给你听呢
Ur… Just wait a sec.
等等
What？
怎么了
I really like you.
我很喜欢你
What is it？
怎么了
It's okay。It's okay.
没关系 没关系
Take all the time you need.
我们慢慢来
Hi，May I help you？
你好 有什么事吗
- Is Kim here？- Yeah，and you are…
- 金姆在吗 - 在 你是
Her father.
她父亲
Mr。Mills，what a pleasure.
米尔斯先生 见到你真荣幸
I'm Jamie.
我是杰米
Come in.
请进
Can I get you anything？A drink？
要喝点什么吗
Just my daughter will be fine.
我女儿就好
Dad？
爸爸
What are you doing here？
你来干什么
I know how important it is for you to pass your test.
我知道通过考试对你来说有多重要
Wait。Kim，you don't have a license？
等等 金姆 你没有驾照吗
Have you ever tried to parallel park an Escalade？
那你试过平行停放凯迪拉克吗
I told you to take the test with my car.
我说了你可以开我的车去考试
God。Dad.
是吗 爸爸
Thank you.
谢谢
A pleasure to meet you，Mr。Mills.
见到你很荣幸 米尔斯先生
Could we slow down a little bit，please？
可以稍微开慢点吗
I can't believe you just did that.
我不敢相信你会这么干
You're leaving on fall break next week.
下周你就要放秋假了
This is the only time
在我去伊斯坦布尔前
I can get to do this before I go to Istanbul.
这是我唯一能腾出的时间
We planned this。When you make plans，you keep them.
我们计划好了 说到就要做到
No，Dad，you planned this.
不是的 爸爸 是你自己计划的
How did you even find me？
你到底怎么找到我的
Your mom and I were talking.
我和你妈妈谈过了
Why didn't you tell me you have a boyfriend？
为什么不告诉我你有男朋友了
Because I knew you'd overreact…
因为我知道你会反应过度
And I just want to feel normal
即使只是假装的
even if I'm just pretending.
我也想像个正常人一样
- Remember to brake before the stop。- Dad.
- 看见停车标志记住要刹车 - 爸爸
Mom doesn't know where Jamie lives.
妈妈不知道杰米住哪里
GPS？
全球定位系统吗
I had it installed in your phone。I'm sorry.
我装在你的手机里了 我很抱歉
You hear so many scary
当你听到那么多
stories of goings-on with people your age…
发生在你同龄人身上的恐怖事件
Dad，I don't even know how to start feeling normal again…
爸爸 我都不知道怎么回到正常生活
But this definitely isn't it.
但现在这样绝对不是
Kim，you can move.
金姆 可以走了
Use your side mirror.
看着后视镜
Perfect。Why couldn't you do that in the test？
真不错 考试的时候你怎么做不到
I don't know.
我不知道
Maybe I didn't really want a license.
也许我其实不是很想要驾照
Listen…
听我说
Of course I know where you're coming from.
我知道你的出发点
But you have to trust me to figure this out.
但你得让我自己来解决
Don't do this again，please？
别这么干了 好吗
I won't.
好的
And don't go running a background check on him with your friends.
也别叫你朋友对他进行背景调查
I won't.
好的
Okay.
好
See you Wednesday.
下周三见
Two o'clock.
两点
Love you.
爱你
Hey，I love you.
我爱你
Sam。Hi。It's me.
山姆 是我
Listen。I want you to run a check on someone。Jamie Conrad.
帮我人肉一个叫杰米·康拉德的人
The usual。Not too deep.
和往常一样 不需要挖太多
You got it.
没问题
Okay。Thanks.
好的 谢谢
- Sir。- Thank you.
- 先生 - 谢谢
Mr。Pitrel？
皮催尔先生
I have a registered letter for you.
有你的挂号信
Can you take that up，Sebastien？
帮我拿一下好吗 塞巴斯坦
Yes，sir.
是的 先生
Here.
给
Sebastien？
塞巴斯坦
Where is he？
他在哪里
I told you.
我说了
I don't know.
我不知道
Where is he？
他在哪里
Okay.
行
You want to play with me.
想跟我玩花样
No，no！
不 不
But I'm a good player，too.
我的花样也不少
Look.
看
No，no！
不 不
I guess the rules are changing.
游戏规则变了
This man came to Paris.
这个人来到巴黎
He used a card to come into our house
他用这张名片进到我们的房子
and kill my friends.
杀了我朋友
And my brother.
也杀了我兄弟
This is your card.
用的就是你的名片
Where is he？
他在哪
Stu，where are you going？Come back！
斯图 你去哪 回来
What's happened？Are you okay？
发生什么了 你还好吗
Yeah，I'm great.
我很好
Come in。I'll get Kim.
进来吧 我去喊金姆
Lennie，talk to me.
莉妮 跟我说说
We had this trip planned to China for Kim's spring break…
我们计划在金姆放春假的时候去中国旅游
as a family，to try and work things out.
一家人一起 看能不能把问题给解决了
And when Stu and I…
当斯图和我
I just thought it would be nice for Kim and I
我只是觉得我和金姆一起出去
to be away together…
会好一些
Away from all the tension.
可以释放点压力
He canceled everything.
但他取消了所有安排
All the reservations.
所有预定
I just can't believe he did this to us.
我不敢相信他居然这么做
I'm just so tired.
我觉得好累
Just the fighting，the lawyers.
不断地争执 还有离婚律师
He's turned into such a bastard.
他变成了一个混蛋
I'm sorry，Lennie.
我很抱歉 莉妮
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry。This is really not your problem.
我很抱歉 这不是你的问题
It's my turn to have…
应该由我来
I'll figure it out.
我会解决这些问题的
Look…
听我说
Why don't you and Kim come with me？
不如你和金姆跟我一起去吧
But we can't impose on you。You're working.
但我们不能打扰你 你要工作
You're not imposing.
不会打扰到我的
I'm working for three days.
我只工作三天
Then you can come over.
然后你们就可以过来了
It could be fun.
会很好玩的
I don't know。I can't think right now.
我不知道 我现在心里很乱
Sure，I understand。No pressure.
没事 我明白 不要有压力
I leave in the morning。I work three days。Call me.
我明早出发 工作三天 给我打电话
If you're coming，I'll hang around.
如果你们来 我就多待几天
If not，I'll come back.
如果不来 我就回来
That's it.
就这么定了
I'll go get kim.
我去叫金姆
Okay.
好的
Thank you，Bryan.
谢谢 布莱恩
She is definitely coming.
她一定会来的
- I don't know。- Come on.
- 我不知道 - 拜托
Oh，come on，Sam，I don't know.
萨姆 别说了 我不知道
You should have insisted.
你应该坚持让她来
Come on，guys。Cut me some slack.
别纠结了 伙计们 放过我吧
She's going through a hard time.
她最近过的很艰难
I didn't want to make it harder on her.
我不想再给她添乱了
She was confiding in me.
她很相信我
Oh！I didn't know you guys were still so cozy…
没想到你们还这么亲密啊
That she shares her marriage issues with you.
她的婚姻问题都跟你说
Wait a minute.
等等
I know you guys were close，obviously，
很明显 你们过去很亲近
but are you close again？
不过现在你们又和好了吗
Close like…
就像
I'll lay money she's still got something for him.
我打赌她还对他有感觉
Don't go there，friend.
都说到哪儿去了 朋友
Maybe he still has something for her！
也许是他对她有感觉
Can we talk about basketball？
我们能聊聊篮球吗
For god's sake，come on！
我的老天 别说这个了
（阿尔巴尼亚 地拉那）
Istanbul.
伊斯坦布尔
Thank you，Mr。Mills.
谢谢 米尔斯先生
You made my stay feel very secure.
你让我在这里很有安全感
Thank you。Have a safe trip home.
谢谢 一路顺风
You also.
你也是
You've reached Lenore。Leave a message after the beep.
我是丽诺尔 听到哔声后请留言
Hey，it's me.
是我
No message from you…
没听到你的消息
So I guess you probably found some place to go.
我猜你可能有别的地方去了
I hope things are a little easier.
希望你没那么难受了
If you ever need to talk or anything，I'm here.
如果你需要聊聊 有我在
I mean，I'll be there.
我会陪着你的
I'll probably ship out tomorrow.
我大概明天乘船离开
No news from Kim.
没有金姆的消息
I guess she's busy with the boyfriend and all.
估计和她男友在一起吧
Dad.
爸爸
Surprise！
惊喜吧
Oh，my God。Kim，baby.
我的天 金姆 宝贝
- Hey，Lennie。- Hello，Bryan.
- 莉妮 - 布莱恩
I was just leaving you a message。When I didn't hear，it was…
我正给你留言 没听到消息 我
We wanted to surprise you.
我们想给你个惊喜
Well，you succeeded.
你们成功了
You guys could have been surprised.
你们真让我惊喜
I could have been out of here and headed home.
我可能离开这里回家去了
Mom's been calling Sam.
妈妈给萨姆打过电话了
- Oh，yeah？- Uh-huh。Yes.
- 是吗 - 没错
We've been tracking you.
我们在追踪你
Exactly。You're not the only one who's got moves.
对 可不是只有你一个会随机应变
Apparently not.
显然不是
Welcome to Istanbul.
欢迎来到伊斯坦布尔
Not too shabby，huh？
不算差吧
Oh，my God.
天哪
Mom，look at this.
妈妈 快来看
Oh，my God！
天哪
It's crazy，right？
太棒了
It's beautiful！
真漂亮
- Thank you so much。- My pleasure.
- 真是太感谢你了 - 我的荣幸
So，listen，I'll let you get settled…
那么 你们先收拾一下
and I'll come and collect you in half an hour？
我半小时之后来接你们
Okay.
好的
Later.
等会见
Good morning.
早上好
Good.
好了
Go.
走吧
- Let's go。- Fast.
- 走吧 - 快走吧
You look great.
你气色不错
You，too.
你也是
So，where are we heading？
那么 我们去哪儿
Well，I am going nowhere。I'm beat.
我哪儿也不去 我累死了
I'm just going to take a nice long bath and get into bed.
我要好好泡个澡再上床休息
Lennie。Are you sure？
莉妮 你确定吗
Yeah.
确定
I guess it's just you and me，kiddo.
那就只剩我和你了 姑娘
Anything special you'd like to do？
你有特别想去的地方吗
Kind of。Maybe.
算有吧
You ready to take off，too？
你也打算走了吗
No，I thought I'd stick around for a couple of more hours.
不呢 我打算在逗留几个小时
- Really？- Yeah.
- 真的吗 - 真的
- Cool。- No。Just kidding.
- 爽啊 - 假的 我说笑的
- Come on。Let's go。- All right。It's so crazy here.
- 我们走吧 - 好吧 这儿可真疯狂
On this side is Europe，and the other side is Asia.
这边是欧洲 那边是亚洲
And every conquest since，for the last 2，500 years…
在过去的2500年间 所有的战争
whether it was the west going east or the east going west…
不论是西方侵略东方还是东方攻击西方
they all used this very same waterway.
都要经过这条水路
- You want some tea，baby？- Yeah.
- 想喝茶吗 宝贝 - 好的
Just one，please.
一杯就好 谢谢
How do you know all this stuff？
你怎么知道这些事情的
How do I know it？
我怎么知道的吗
I read it in a book on the flight over.
我坐飞机过来时 在书上看到的
And you can borrow it if you wish.
如果想看的话可以借你
Yeah，I would.
好的
So，this Jamie…
对那个杰米
Is it… serious？
你是认真的吗
That was a really smooth transition.
话题转换得还真是自然啊
I don't know.
我不知道
It's only been a few months.
才几个月而已
Are you in love with him？
你爱他吗
I guess I'm not sure yet.
我还不确定
Have you ever been in love before？
那你原来爱过谁吗
Not… not the way that mom talks about it.
都不是妈妈说的那种
How does she describe it？
她怎么说的
She said when you guys met…
她说你们相遇的时候
That…it was super special.
非常特别
Super special？She said that？
非常特别 她这么说的吗
I think the exact word she used was…
她的原话是
「Magical.」
神奇
Magical，huh？
神奇吗
It's good to see you again，my friend.
再次见到你很高兴 朋友
Is everything prepared？
都准备好了吗
As you requested.
都按你要求准备好了
Ah！Perfect.
很好
- Yeah？- He's in the lobby.
- 怎么样 - 他在大厅
Wait until he's outside.
等他出来再动手
And remember，alive.
记住 抓活的
He's on to me。I'm leaving.
他注意到我了 我要走了
I thought we were having lunch in the bazaar.
我以为我们是要去集市上吃饭
Jet lag just hit me.
我时差还没倒过来
So I figured l'd veg out by the pool and let you guys go.
所以想到泳池边放松一下 你们去吧
Meet up with you later？
晚点见
- I guess。Okay with you？- Of course。It's fine.
- 好的 你一个人可以吗 - 当然 可以啊
- Oh，okay。Bye。- Hey，Kim.
- 好的 拜拜 - 金姆
That book I was telling you about？It's on my dresser.
我跟你说的那本书 在我的梳妆台上
Definitely.
明白
No adventuring。I'll go call the car.
别到处跑 我去叫车
Have fun.
好好玩
Hey，Kim.
金姆
l know what you're doing.
我知道你的小把戏
What？
什么
Yeah？
怎么了
The daughter is staying here。What can we do？
他女儿待在旅店 要怎么办
I want all three of them.
一个都不放过
Yes.
对
She thinks we just fell off the turnip truck.
她把我们想得太天真了
What do you mean？
什么意思
She's trying to play Cupid.
她想当个丘比特
I see.
我明白了
You know，when you first came back，
你第一次回来的时候
and said you wanted to make up for all that time
你说想弥补
that you lost with Kim？
亏欠金姆的时间
I thought，「Right，three weeks，he's gone.」
我以为 好吧 他最多能待三个星期
That was usually about the limit you stuck around.
通常你也只能待那么长时间
Give or take a week.
相差也不过一周左右
Not too close.
别跟太紧
You really proved me wrong.
事实证明我错了
I thought you'd never change.
我以为你永远不会改变
Why not？
为什么不会
Your personality.
本性难移吧
When you commit to something，
你每做一件事情
you focus all your energy there，
都会全力以赴
like a dog with a bone.
就像狗啃骨头一样
Nice analogy.
比喻很形象
You know what I mean.
你知道我的意思
When you give，it's 100 percent of 100 percent.
你做事时都是百分百的投入
If I was on to something，it was just that thing.
过去我做一件事 就只会想那件事
Even though I tell myself I should change，
即便我告诫自己要有所改变
I could never give it up.
我还是无法放弃
You gave us up.
你放弃了我们
No，never.
没有 永远不会
Not in here.
这里绝不会放弃
Driver，turn left.
司机 麻烦左转
Lennie，don't.
莉妮 别回头
What？
怎么了
Will you tell me what's going on？
能不能告诉我怎么了
It's okay.
没事
Where is he？
去哪了
You see the gallery entrance in the middle of the block？
看到中间那家画廊了吗
- Will you tell me what's going on？- Do you see it？
- 能不能告诉我怎么了 - 看到了吗
Yeah，I see it.
看到了
When we stop，
车一停
I want you to get out of the car like you're a shopper.
你就下车假装要去购物
I want you to go inside.
然后进去
Will you tell me what's going on？
能不能告诉我怎么了
Listen to me.
听我说
Lennie，there's no time for this.
莉妮 没时间了
- Just talk to me！- Listen.
- 快告诉我 - 听着
When you exit the back of the fabric store，turn right.
然后从针织店后门出来 再右转
Take the first street on the right，
第一路口再右转
then left on the very next street.
紧接着下一个路口左转
Go straight until you come to a set of steps.
直走一直到一段台阶
There's a red corridor。It's a lane.
那儿有个红色走廊 是条小巷
When you exit the lane，there's a cab stand.
出了小巷 有个出租车站
Go back to the hotel.
回到酒店
Get Kim。Get the head of hotel security，
找到金姆 然后去找酒店的保安主管
and demand that he cordon off your room.
要求他在你们房间周围布好警戒
Do not open the door for anyone.
任何人敲门都不要开
No room service，no police，no one.
客户服务 警察 谁都别开门
You wait for me.
在房间里等我
I can't believe this is happening.
这到底是怎么一回事啊
I need you to focus.
你得集中精力
Are you ready？
准备好了吗
No.
没有
I need you to be ready。I need you to be ready.
我需要你做好准备 你必须做好准备
Come on，focus.
快 集中精神
Driver，stop.
司机 停车
Okay，go.
好 去吧
Wait，what about you？
等等 你怎么办
I'll be fine.
我没事
It's the guys following us who are about to have a problem.
该当心的是跟踪我们的那帮小子
When a dog has a bone，
狗叼着骨头的时候
the last thing you want to do is try and take it from him.
千万别跟它抢
Be careful.
小心
Out of the car.
下车
Come on。Move，move，move！
快点 起来 起来
Sir！Please.
先生 拜托
Please。Sir！
拜托 先生
He knows.
被他发现了
Do it now.
动手吧
Come on.
快点
Shit.
该死
Come on，Kim，answer the goddamn phone.
快 金姆 快接电话
He's gone！
让他跑了
Oh，God，no！Somebody help me！
老天 帮帮我
The key！Open the door，please！
钥匙 拜托 帮我开下门
Shit！
该死
I'll blow his brains out.
再过来我就打爆他的头
Bryan！
布莱恩
Please！
求你了
Drop the gun.
把枪放下
I really wish you were here.
我真希望你也在这儿
Me too。You have no idea.
我也是 你不知道我有多想
What？
怎么了
My dad's calling.
我老爸的电话
He's on a date with my mom.
他正和我妈约会呢
I'll call you right back.
一会再聊
Miss you。Bye.
想你 再见
How's it going？
怎么样了
Listen to me carefully Kim.
认真听我说 金姆
Your mother and I
我和你妈妈
are going to be taken.
被人挟持了
Daddy！
老爸
Oh，my God.
老天爷
And people are going to come for you，too.
那帮人也会去找你
Leave the place where you are calmly.
悄悄地离开
Go to where the book is I told you about.
去我跟你说放那本书的地方
There's a door。Go into the room and hide in the closet.
有扇门 开门进去 藏到衣橱里
- You got that？- Yes.
- 听明白了吗 - 明白
Good。I'll call you.
好 我会打电话给你
Go，now.
现在就去
No！
不要
She is in room 422.
她在422房间
No！No！
不 不要
One，
一
two，
二
three，
三
four，
四
five
五
six.
六
Right turn.
右转
Man singing.
男人的歌声
One，
一
two，
二
three，
三
four.
四
Boat.
有船
The pool！
游泳池
Security，fourth floor.
保安 这是四楼
Do you copy me？
听到了吗
Send someone now.
马上派人过来
Twenty-five，
二十五
twenty-six，
二十六
twenty-seven，
二十七
twenty-eight，
二十八
twenty-nine.
二十九
Stop.
停
She's not here.
她不在这儿
Not here？
不在这儿
Check her dad's room.
去她爸房间看看
Hammer on metal.
敲击金属的声音
Left。Gear shift to second.
左转 换到二档
One，two，three.
一 二 三
Birds.
鸟叫声
You have them？
抓到他们了吗
Yes，Efendi。Both.
是的 阿凡提 两个都带来了
Take them to the shop，straight.
把他们直接带到店里去
Look！
看
A flip-flop.
一双人字拖
You go left！
你走左边
Right turn.
右转
Twenty-seven.
二十七
Stop.
停车
No！No！
不要 不要
I shot some guy！
我开的枪
Come on，Sam。Pick up.
快 萨姆 接电话
Hey，this is Sam。Leave me a message.
你好 我是萨姆 请留言
Shit.
妈的
Are you guys okay？
你们还好吗
No，no。Are you all right？
不好 你还好吗
Yes.
我没事
I'm just scared.
我很害怕
Kim，listen to me very carefully.
金姆 仔细听我说
I need you to calm down and pull yourself together.
你要冷静 集中精神
Okay.
好的
The men who came for you，did they leave？
来抓你的人走了吗
Yes。What do they want？
走了 他们想干什么
I'm going to find out.
我会查清楚的
Is mom okay？
妈妈还好吗
Dad.
爸爸
Mom's fine.
妈妈没事
Okay.
好
What are we going to do？
我们怎么办
I want you to go to the US Embassy。You'll be safe there.
去美国大使馆 那里很安全
What about you and Mom？
你和妈妈呢
I'll figure something out.
我会想到办法的
Where are you now？
你现在在哪儿
I don't really know，Kim.
我也不确定 金姆
Dad，how can I tell them where to find you，then？
爸爸 那我让他们去哪儿找你
You can't。Now get going.
不需要 你快走
No.
不
Kimmie.
金姆
No。Tell me what to do.
不 告诉我该怎么做
No，Kim.
不行 金姆
Dad，if you tell me what to do，I can do it.
爸爸 你跟我说该做什么 我能做到
Kim，this is not a game.
金姆 这不是一场游戏
I know that。It's my parents' lives.
我知道 事关我父母的生死
Dad，please.
爸爸 拜托
You're wasting time.
你在浪费时间
Please.
快告诉我
Tell me what to do.
告诉我该怎么做
Can you get out of the closet safely？
你能安全离开衣橱吗
Yes.
可以
If you can，take the case with you.
如果可以的话 带上箱子
Okay.
好的
I'm out.
出来了
The combination is 232884.
密码是232884
- Is it open？- Yeah.
- 打开了吗 - 打开了
Okay。Do you see a map？
好的 看到地图了吗
Yeah.
看到了
Take the map.
打开地图
You'll see a scale on the top in kilometers.
地图上方有比例尺
Do you see it？
看到了吗
Yeah，I see it.
看到了
Take a shoelace from one of my shoes in the closet.
从衣橱里的鞋上扯根鞋带
Use it as a guide.
用它做标尺
There's a pen in the case.
箱子里有支钢笔
Take it.
拿出来
Draw a circle with the hotel in the center of it.
以酒店为中心画个圆
- It's done。-Make the diameter three kilometers.
- 好了 - 以三千米为直径
You got that？
听明白了吗
- It's done。-Draw another circle with the market in the center.
- 画好了 - 以超市为中心再画一个圆
- Okay。- Do the circles intersect at any points？
- 好了 - 两个圆有交点吗
No.
没有
Now，take one of those little cans，
拿出一个小罐子
the ones with the pins on the top.
上面有插销的那种
It's a grenade.
那是手榴弹
I want you to go to the balcony with the grenade.
拿着手榴弹去阳台
Is there a safe place you can throw it？
有安全的地方可以扔吗
There's a parking garage.
有个停车场
Anyone on it？
里面有人吗
No.
没有
I want you to pull the pin out of the grenade，
把手榴弹的插销拔掉
count to three so I can hear it，
数到三 要让我听见
Then toss it as far as you can.
尽量扔远一点
And then run back into the room.
然后立即跑回房间
Keep the phone on so I can hear the explosion.
别挂电话 我要听见爆炸声
One.
一
Two.
二
Three.
三
One.
一
Two.
二
Three.
三
Four.
四
Dad？
爸爸
Now draw a circle on the map with the hotel in the middle，
现在在地图上以酒店为中心画个圆
and the circumference at 4.5 kilometers.
周长四千五百米
- Ok。-Do the circles intersect at any points？
- 好了 - 有交点了吗
Yeah，at two points.
有两个交点
I'm at one of the two intersecting points.
我就在其中一个交点附近
Now go outside and look at the flags on the rooftops.
现在去外面看看房顶上的旗帜
Do you see the flags？
看到旗帜了吗
- Yes。- Are they in the wind？
- 看到了 - 有风吗
- Yeah。- Going east，right？
- 有 - 向东飘 对吗
I think so，yeah。How did you know？
我想是的 你怎么知道的
Now look at the map.
看看地图
I want you to go to the point
你到东边那个交点
where the circles intersect at the east.
所在的位置去
I want you to take one of the guns，
带上一支手枪
get to a rooftop，wait for my call.
到屋顶 等我电话
And two of the grenades.
再带上两个手榴弹
Go to the rooftop at the most easterly point.
到最东侧的屋顶
Get up to the rooftop。Wait for my call.
到屋顶后等我电话
Be casual，Kim。Blend in.
小心点 金姆 不要被发现
Okay.
好
Dad？
爸爸
Who are you？
你是谁
Those clothes don't belong to you.
那衣服不是你的
Help！
来人啊
There's a thief in here！
抓小偷啊
You know this man？
你认识这人吗
This one？
这个呢
No.
不认识
This one？
这个呢
What do you want？
你到底想干什么
You recognize none of them.
这些人你都不认识
To you，they were nothing.
对你来说 他们没有任何意义
But to other people，
但对有些人来说
they are sons and grandsons.
他们是儿子和孙子
Fathers and husbands.
父亲还有丈夫
And you killed them all.
而你把他们全杀了
Like they were so many nothings.
在你眼里他们一文不值
And this one？
这个人呢
You recognize him？
你认识他吗
You do recognize him.
你应该认识他
Him，you didn't just kill.
你没有直接杀了他
Him，you strapped to a chair.
而是把他绑在椅子上
You attached electric cables to the chair.
给椅子接上电缆
You turned the current on，
接通电源
and you left it on until his heart burst.
活活把他电死
He's the one who kidnapped
他拐骗了几十个女孩
dozens of girls and ruined their lives.
毁了她们的生活
He was my son.
他是我儿子
Marko，from Tropoje.
马可 来自特罗波耶
And I have come to take you to Tropoje
我来是想把你带到特罗波耶
to face you to the people whose lives you have ruined.
让你看看你是如何毁了别人的生活
To give them justice.
还他们一个公道
You mean to give them revenge.
你是想为他们报仇
If it gives us peace，
只要能给我们带来安宁
call it anything you wish.
你爱怎么说随便
I killed your son because he kidnapped my daughter.
我杀你儿子是因为他绑架了我女儿
I don't care what he did！
我不管他做过什么
I only know I will never see his face again.
我只知道我再也看不到他的脸
I will never hear his voice.
再也听不到他的声音
And as you held him responsible for your daughter，
既然你为你女儿杀了他
I hold you responsible for him.
我就要让你为他的死负责
Your death will not be quick.
我不会让你痛痛快快地死
It will not be pleasant.
我要让你求生不得 求死不能
But before you die，
但在你死之前
this is what you will see.
我要让你看看
Bring her in.
把她带过来
Bryan.
布莱恩
How long will it take for the blood to rush to her head，
血液全部冲满脑袋
and have no place to go？
再从伤口流出来需要多长时间
About 30 minutes.
大概三十分钟
You are right。You're an expert for this.
没错 你真是行家
So you have 30 minutes to watch her die.
就是说这三十分钟你只能眼睁睁看着她死
She had nothing to do with this.
这不关她的事
Do what you want with me。Let her go.
有什么冲我来 让她走
Don't play the hero with me.
别跟我逞英雄
Now we are going to catch your daughter.
我们马上就会抓到你女儿
She will be sold to the lowest brothel in this world.
她会被卖到最低级的妓院
No！No！
不要 不要
She will be abused by so many men
被无数男人凌辱
that she'll be nothing more
变成一坨烂肉
than a piece of meat a dog would not have.
连狗都不理
Don't listen to them，Lennie.
别听他们胡说 莉妮
Kim is safe.
金姆很安全
I spoke with her.
我跟她通了话
She's safe.
她很安全
You have to stay calm。Breathe slowly.
你得保持冷静 慢慢呼吸
You have to.
你必须这样做
I won't let anything happen to you，or to her.
我绝不会让你们两个出事
I promise.
我保证
Hello，Murad？
穆拉德
Quiet.
安静
We lost the girl.
我们没抓到那女孩
The girl has gone.
那女孩跑掉了
I'll be back as soon as we get her，then we move.
我抓到她就回来 然后我们再走
Come on！
我们走
Hold on，Lennie.
撑住 莉妮
Hold on，Lennie。Hold on.
撑住 莉妮 撑住
What's he doing？
他干什么呢
Get out of the way！
别挡路
- Sorry！Sorry！- Come back！You have to pay！
- 抱歉 抱歉 - 回来 你还没付钱
Lennie.
莉妮
I'm with you，baby。I'm here。I'm here.
我来了 亲爱的 我在这 我在这
Come on。Call.
快点 快打电话来
Please，come on.
求你了 快点
Lennie.
莉妮
Lennie。Lennie.
莉妮 莉妮
I'm coming back.
我马上回来
I'm here.
我到了
Set off another grenade.
再扔个手榴弹
- Dad？- You're close.
- 爸爸 - 已经很近了
I want you to keep moving east.
你一直往东走
Count to 30 and then set off another one.
数三十下 然后再扔一个
One，two，three.
一 二 三
Eighteen，nineteen，
十八 十九
twenty-six，twenty-seven，
二十六 二十七
twenty-eight，twenty-nine，
二十八 二十九
thirty.
三十
Go out and check what's going on.
出去看看什么情况
- Kim。- Yeah.
- 金姆 - 我在
Look east。Look for a white cloud of steam.
向东看 有没有一团白蒸汽
I see it.
看到了
Run to it。Tell me when you're there.
跑过去 到了告诉我
I'm going down.
我下去看看
- Dad。- Where are you？
- 爸爸 - 你在哪儿
I'm right by the steam.
我就在蒸汽这里
Drop the gun down the vent.
把枪从排气口扔下来
Oh，god，they're here。They're coming.
天啊 他们来了 他们来了
Drop the gun，Kim，and run.
把枪扔下来 金姆 然后快跑
Go.
跑
Dad！They're coming.
爸爸 他们来了
I'm coming back.
我马上回来
Drop that.
放下
On your knees！
跪下
Don't do this.
别杀我
Please.
求你了
Dad？
爸爸
Dad！Dad！
爸爸 爸爸
Baby.
宝贝
Where's Mom？Is she okay？
妈妈在哪里 她还好吗
She's safe。She's safe.
她很安全 很安全
Slow down，slow down，slow down.
慢点 慢点 慢点
I've got a fare.
我有生意了
That man had the same tattoo as the men in paris.
那人身上的刺青跟巴黎那些人一样
It's not you they want，Kim。It's me.
他们要的不是你 金姆 是我
I want you to wait here。I'm going to get Mom.
你在这里等着 我去救妈妈
Wait five minutes，and if I don't show up，
如果五分钟之后我还没出来
I want you to go straight here，to the American Embassy.
你就直接去美国大使馆
- Tell them what happened。- Dad.
- 告诉他们发生了什么 - 爸爸
No time，Kim。Give me your phone.
没时间了 金姆 手机拿过来
You wait five minutes，not a moment longer.
只等五分钟 一秒也不要多等
No matter what happens，time runs out，you go.
无论发生什么 时间一到你就走
You understand me？
明白吗
Okay.
好的
No！
不
No.
Bryan.
布莱恩
Yes？
怎么了
- Move！- You killed him.
- 快走 - 你杀了他
I had no choice。Move.
我别无选择 快走
- Where's Mom？- She's fine，she's not far.
- 妈妈在哪 - 她没事 就在附近
- Where is she？- Come on，Kim，move！
- 她在哪里 - 快点 金姆 快走
- I don't want to do this。- Keep going，Kim.
- 我不想这么做 - 继续走 金姆
Where are we going？
我们去哪里
Go straight。We have to go to the Embassy.
直走 我们得去大使馆
I'm not sure I can.
我可能做不到
- Do you know how to shoot？- No.
- 你会开枪吗 - 不会
Then drive.
那就老实开车
They escaped.
他们跑掉了
Officer down in Balat.
巴拉特区有警官遇害
Copy.
收到
Shit，cops.
妈的 有警察
Dad，I have to stop.
爸爸 我得停车
No，I just shot one of them。Now，go.
不行 我刚打死了一个 快走
Come on，go！
快点 走
Right.
右转
Back，back，back！
快倒 快 快
Come on，move！
快点 走
Come on，Kim.
快点 金姆
Go，go！
走 走
Faster.
加速
Come on。Keep going.
继续走
- Left！- Yeah.
- 左转 - 好的
They're in the taxi！
他们在那辆出租车上
Keep going.
继续走
- Oh，no。- Shit.
- 不 - 妈的
Stay low。Keep going.
趴低点 继续走
- Come on，faster。- I can't.
- 快点 加速 - 不行了
- Do it！- I can't！
- 你行的 - 我做不到
Come on，move！Move.
快点 闪开 闪开
- Dad！- Keep going.
- 爸爸 - 继续走
Move！
走
Right.
右转
Oh，shit.
该死
No！
不
Come on，Kim。Move！
快点 金姆 快走
- Go！Go！- Okay。I'm trying.
- 走 走 - 好 我在走
Come on，keep going.
快点 继续走
Turn left.
左转
Shit.
该死
Dad！
爸爸
Keep going。Stay low.
继续走 趴低点
- Faster，Kim。- I can't.
- 再快点 金姆 - 我做不到
- Come on，faster！- Dad！
- 加油 再快点 - 爸爸
Keep going.
继续走
You can make it.
你能做到
Do it.
冲过去
（美国大使馆）
Here！Don't stop.
就是这 别停下
But the soldiers.
但那些士兵
They'll move.
他们会闪开的
Down，Kim！
趴下 金姆
Nobody shoot.
不要开枪
It's a suicide bomber.
那是个汽车炸弹
Are you okay？
你还好吗
Yeah.
还好
Keep your head down，Kimmie.
把头低下 金姆
Hey Bryan.
布莱恩
Sam，we're in a courtyard of the U.S。Embassy in Istanbul
萨姆 我们在伊斯坦布尔的美国大使馆
in a smashed-up car.
院子里的一辆破车里
Don't ask.
别问为什么
Can you call someone to make sure we don't get shot？
你能让他们别向我们开枪吗
Yeah，of course.
当然没问题
Thanks.
多谢
It's Bry。He's in trouble in Istanbul.
是布莱恩 他在伊斯坦布尔有麻烦了
Mom didn't get away，did she？
妈妈没逃出来 是吗
No.
是的
Oh，God，dad.
天啊 爸爸
Tell me the truth。Is she…
跟我说实话 她是不是…
No，no，no，kim。No，she's not.
不不不 金姆 她没死
But they have her.
但她在他们手上
And they will use her until they get what they want.
他们会利用她得到他们想要的东西
Me.
就是我
You'll be safe here in the Embassy until I come back.
我回来之前 你待在大使馆会很安全
Kimmie，it's going to be okay.
金姆 会没事的
Nothing's okay.
一切都糟透了
Kim，Kim，listen.
金姆 金姆 听着
I have to find them.
我必须找到他们
And bring your mom back.
把你妈妈带回来
And then I have to make sure these people
而且我要确保这些人
never bother us again in our lives.
今后再也不会找我们的麻烦
What are you going to do？
你要做什么
What I do best.
做我最拿手的
Mrs。Mills.
米尔斯夫人
What should I do with you，Mrs。Mills？
我该拿你怎么办呢 米尔斯夫人
I have nothing against you.
我不是针对你
You didn't kill my son.
我儿子不是你杀的
But your husband did.
但是你丈夫杀的
Now，he betrayed you by choosing
现在 他背叛了你
to save your daughter instead of you.
他选择去救你们的女儿 而不是你
He left you here like a dog.
他把你像狗一样丢在这
At least my daughter is still alive.
至少我女儿还活着
Mrs。Mills，you're a good mother，
米尔斯夫人 你是个好母亲
and a brave woman.
也是个勇敢的女人
For that，I'm going to send you back home
所以 我会把你送回家
Piece by piece.
一块一块地送回去
Shut up！
闭嘴
Ohri，shoot this dog.
欧利 快毙了那条狗
Go and see what's happened.
去看看怎么回事
Let's go。Move through here，to the hammam.
我们走 这边 去浴场
Hurry！Hurry！
快 快
Mirko！
米尔科
You stay here.
你留在这
No！
不
No.
No。Bryan！
不 布莱恩
Come on！
快走
You can't come in！
你不能进来
Get lost.
闪开
Lennie.
莉妮
I'm here，baby。I'm here.
我在这 亲爱的 我在这
I'm coming back，Lennie。I'm coming back.
我回来了 我回来了
Okay？
好吗
What are you waiting for？
你还等什么
You have other sons？
你还有其他儿子吗
Two.
两个
And if I killed you，they will come and seek revenge.
如果我杀了你 他们会来找我报仇
They will，for sure.
当然 毫无疑问
And I will kill them，too.
那我也会把他们杀了
You can change that.
你能改变这一切
You can go home，live your life.
你可以回家 好好生活
Enjoy your sons，your grandsons.
跟儿孙共聚天伦
And my other son，
那我另一个儿子
Marko.
马可
The son you killed.
你杀死的那个
Am I supposed to just forget it？
我应该就这么忘了吗
No.
不
You will just have to live with it，
你应该接受这个现实
Like the parents of all those kidnapped girls.
就像那些被绑架的女孩的父母一样
Or you can die here.
不然你就会死在这里
What are you telling me？
你是什么意思
What I'm saying is，if you give me your word，
我的意思是 如果你向我保证
I will throw down this gun and simply walk away.
我就把枪扔掉 离开这里
Why？
为什么
Because I am tired of it all.
因为我厌倦了这一切
Lennie，I'm here.
莉妮 我在这
I'm here，baby。I'm here.
我在这 亲爱的 我在这
Come on，baby.
起来 亲爱的
It's okay。It's okay.
没事了 没事了
It's okay.
没事了
We're safe.
我们安全了
Bryan.
布莱恩
Kim.
金姆
She's safe.
她没事
她很安全
We're all safe.
我们都没事了
（三周后）
（车管所 此处仅限报考者）
Okay.
好的
Line it up.
车身摆正
That's it.
没错
Now，begin to cut.
现在 开始倒车
Not too fast，not too fast.
别太快 别太快
Straighten it out。Straighten，straighten.
方向盘回正 回正 回正
That's it.
好了
Stop，stop，stop.
停 停 停
Perfect.
太棒了
Well，perfect score.
满分
Great！
太好了
Congratulations.
祝贺你
Thank you.
谢谢
I was perfect.
我做得很完美
I've been saying that since the day you were born.
从你出生那天起我就这么说
Congratulations.
祝贺你
So，what would you like to do to celebrate？
你想怎么庆祝
I think I have an idea.
我有个主意
Yeah？
是吗
Yeah。I'll drive.
是的 我来开车
Of course.
当然
Don't knock it till you try it
努力之前 不言放弃
Just come out to LA
走出家门 奔向洛城
Here you go。Three double-chocolate fudge.
来了 三份双层巧克力乳脂软糖冰淇淋
Thank you.
谢谢
Who's having the strawberry？
这份草莓的给谁
I'm sorry，but I just ordered three.
不好意思 我只点了三份
Actually，the order said four.
但单子上写了四份
I ordered the fourth one.
是我点的
For who？
给谁的
Oh，Jamie.
杰米
Hi。Perfect timing.
来的正好
Jamie.
杰米
It's cool if he joins us，right？
他可以跟我们一起 对吧
Of course it is，honey.
当然可以 亲爱的
Dad？
爸爸
- Of course it is，honey。- Behave.
- 当然可以 亲爱的 - 礼貌点
It's nice to see you again，sir.
再次见到你很高兴 先生
Nice to see you，too。Sit down.
也很高兴见到你 坐下吧
We got you a strawberry.
我们给你点了份草莓的
Oh，please.
少说两句吧
Thanks，dad.
多谢 爸爸
Don't shoot this one。I really like him.
这人你可不能打 我真的很喜欢他